JU YOUNG KIM

juyoung.kim517@gmail.com +821076460746 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ju-young-kim-048215b6 GitHub Resume: https://juyoungkimthedev.github.io/resume

Summary

I have 5 years of software engineering experience mostly in fast-paced and agile startup companies with focus in fintech ranging from banking and insurance to payments. I have lots of hands-on experience building RESTful web services and ETL data pipeline for machine learning platforms. I have strong teamwork spirit and ethics and I plan to use these skills together with clean and efficient coding strategies to improve company processes and provide most optimal solutions for clients.

Experience

Primer | Backend Software Engineer | London, United Kingdom

February 2022 - Present

- Worked in the core payment application framework team. Developed and maintained Starlette based Python application framework to allow developers to build internal and third-party apps on the payment platform. These apps were the building blocks of the payment platform. Led migration of old apps (not using framework) to the new framework.
- Maintained and improved existing FastAPI based core API by adding new endpoints, handlers and controllers that manage internal and third-party application lifecycle. Tools used: Aiohttp, SQLAlchemy, Kafka.
- Created marketplace API service that connects to the core API to serve app instances and specifications to merchants through a web dashboard, allowing complete app management on the dashboard.
- Reduced time to build and maintain new apps by 80% by creating an automation tool to manage app creation and metadata updates, eliminating frequent alembic data migrations and manual assets upload to S3.

Root | Software Engineer | Cape Town, South Africa

April 2021 – January 2022

- Joined the product team and worked mostly on the server side TypeScript/Node.js code to build new features and maintain a monolith insurance platform. Maintained some frontend dashboard components using React.js.
- Implemented policy pdf document encryption using Node.js qpdf wrapper that automatically password protects policy related documents before sending to clients.
- Ported client product module code execution environment from Node.js vm2 to AWS Lambda functions to allow for more secure code execution and dependency management.
- Improved the legacy React codebase by refactoring to the new internal web architecture. Mostly worked on changing class component code to functional component with React hooks.

Praelexis | Software Engineer & Data Engineer | Cape Town, South Africa

March 2018 - March 2021

- Designed, implemented and deployed highly scalable backend APIs in the Azure cloud environment that serve multiple financial machine learning models for the core credit team at a retail bank. Tools used: Python, Flask, Aiohttp.
- Created and deployed large-scale scheduled data pipelines and machine learning workflows to allow data ingestion, model training, model scoring and data exporting to be used by credit applications. Tools used: Luigi, PySpark, Databricks.
- Contributed to migrating core data lake services built on top of Azure to AWS using EMR, Glue, Athena.

Education

- University of Cape Town: Master of Science: Bioinformatics, 2018
- University of Pretoria: Bachelor of Science Honors in Bioinformatics, 2014
- University of Pretoria: **Bachelor of Science** in Biochemistry, 2013

Technical Skills

- Languages: Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Julia, R, Go, Java
- Frameworks and Libraries: FastAPI, Flask, Aiohttp, SQLAlchemy, Node.js, Express.js, React.js,
- Database: PostgreSQL, CosmosDB, DynamoDB
- Cloud and DevOps: AWS (S3, Lambda, ECR), Azure (Blobstore, AKS), Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform, Heroku
- Data: Databricks, PySpark, Apache Kafka
- Tools: Git, GitLab, Pipeline CI/CD, BitBucket, JIRA, Localstack, VS Code, Postman, PyCharm, Datadog, Feature flags